From Daily Wire published March
20 2026 Afro man's victory is
America's victory Afro man's
victory is America's victory
This unlikely hero proved
doggedly fierce when it came to
fighting for truth justice and
the American way Mar 20 2026
dailywire com Listen to this
article Will Heath NBC via Getty
Images In 2001 Joseph Edgar
Forman better known as Afro man
burst onto the scene with the
now classic song Because I Got
High the title track to his
second album Though he'd been
honing his craft since middle
school that song introduced him
to the masses Since that time
he's released 17 more albums
though Because I Got High
remains his most famous His most
infamous album however is 2022's
Lemon Pound Cake which was a
direct salvo against the police
officers who raided his home on
suspicion of drug trafficking
and kidnapping two crimes which
he did not commit That didn't
stop officers from seizing 5 000
in cash 400 of which was never
returned and causing 20 000 in
damages to his home Afro man
whose first song was a diss
track wasn't inclined to stay
quiet about that injustice
Instead he turned the saga into
the 2022 album On it he called
the officers out by name He used
footage of them from his CCTV
cameras for the videos He
implied that their wives were
cheating on them one with him He
called one fat and said he was
eyeing the Lemon Pound Cake on
his counter during the raid He
was relentless which is
unsurprising given he once said
A skunk has its spray If you
mess with me I rap about your
ass It works It's funny The
officers though were not amused
hitting the entertainer with a
defamation suit in 2023 Afro man
though remained undeterred and
on March 19th 2026 he was found
innocent of all charges saying
We did it America We did it
Freedom of speech He forgot to
add freedom from unlawful search
and seizure For a man who rose
to prominence by rapping about
how getting high was sapping his
motivation this unlikely hero
proved doggedly fierce when it
came to fighting for truth
justice and the American way As
a nation we should be thankful
for Afro man Most would not go
to the lengths would not risk
the financial implications of
failure would not go scorched
earth over 20 400 and a ruined
day But not Afro man He still
believes in the Constitution in
freedom of speech and in the
importance of good and
trustworthy police to the
community Moreover he rampaged
with style For the final day in
court he wore a suit and tie
with an American flag pattern He
Afro maxed His only witness was
the ex wife of an officer whom
Afro man claimed to have slept
with prior to the divorce When
the officer was asked if he knew
for sure that Afro man was not
having relations with his wife
the officer responded I don't
know thereby undermining his own
defamation suit Paul Archuleta
Film Magic Getty Images In short
Afro man tapped into the rugged
pioneer spirit that helped build
this nation and showed that even
in 2026 great men can still
achieve great things if they put
their minds to it Lesser men
would have folded afraid of the
millions in damages the officers
were suing for They would have
worried about the risks of
tangling with local law
enforcement They would have
sucked up the 20 400 they lost
and moved on with their lives
And for many that's okay We
can't all risk everything to
fight injustice Not everyone has
the sort of career and
flexibility that affords us the
opportunity to stand up for
basic rights and dignity As such
we need heroes out there
fighting for us But not all
heroes wear capes Some wear fur
coats over their American flag
suit Afro man you beat the man
in the process You not only won
but we as a nation also won Your
victory is our victory Your
fight is an inspiration for
anyone facing injustice whether
young or old May your success
inspire us all to be as
resilient when faced with the
specter of a boot pounding down
on our cake forever Rich
Cromwell is a writer living in
Northwest Arkansas He produces
the Cooking Up a Story podcast
You can also follow him on X The
views expressed in this piece
are those of the author and do
not necessarily represent those
of The Daily Wire